有啲人未夠。
出席嘅。
官員啦。
啊！團體咧係。
審議嗰個法例啊！
同埋其他嘅誒。
唔緊要，我哋再開住開始咗先。
啊！嚟到進一步去商討。
我哋請嗰啲誒團體代表嚟。
誒保險業監理處啊！
誒，我哋夠法定人數又夠時間開會嚇。
我歡迎副局長同埋誒金管局啊！
我哋今日咧就有誒九個團體咧係。
係到達呢個會場，噉我哋今日咧就有誒九個。
繼續咧係就住呢個金融機構嘅處理機制。
嚟發表佢哋嘅意見嘅，噉我哋今日嘅議程咧就係除咗聽佢哋嘅意見之外咧，都會同政府相關嘅部門咧就係誒。
Okay.
啊，肖女士。
啊！貧土嘅標示嘅啦。
每一位嘅發言時間咧。
展示各種語言嘅嗰個。
Alan and Overy， thanks the Bills Committee for the opportunity to comment on the Financial Institutions Resolution Bill at today's session.
誒需要即時全日服務嘅耳顧人士咧，請大家戴上嗰個耳筒嚇，然後按需要咧去選擇個頻道。座位上面咧已經。
送畀各個委員嘅，為咗方便方便法案委員會誒瞭解團體嘅關注以及政府當局作出回應咧，條例草案誒。
overall，Ellen and Ovary supports the bill，as we consider the bill to be an essential development and evolution of the Hong Kong legal and regulatory regime.
嗱，我代表法案委員會歡迎各位團體代表出席今日嘅會議。就住金融機構處理機制條例草案發表意見，我哋都歡迎咧政府當局嘅代表出席會議嘅。
今日一共有九個誒團體代表啦，另外亦都有十個嚇不出席會議嘅團體誒同埋工作人士咧，向委員會提交咗意見書嘅。我會先請各個團體代表輪流發言。
上發言咧係唔會受到誒立法會嘅權力及特權條例所規定嘅保障同埋豁免嘅。噉我首先咧係請安理國際律師事務所合夥人蕭爾文女士發言。
我哋有四分鐘，噉我希望咧可以有多啲時間咧，我哋一陣間可以作一個交流嘅嚇。發言完畢之後，我會請政府當局咧係作初步嘅回應。委員隨後咧亦都可以向團體嘅代表咧，或者係政府當局係提問嘅。
香港 needs the bill for the following reasons. Firstly, resolution and recovery regimes are recommended internationally by the FSB, the Financial Stability Board, and Hong Kong as a major financial centre needs to have such a regime.
誒根據慣常嘅做法，除非有團體人士嚇佢哋所提交嘅意見書有表明咧，佢哋係唔願意係公開，否則嘅話咧，秘書處會將收到嘅意見書咧係上載喺立法會嘅網頁，同埋咧係誒發。
resolution planning to ensure resolvability.
The Hong Kong bill is broadly in line with the key attributes set out by the FSB.
triggers for resolution. Again, there are various steps and procedures to be met.
examples of main features consistent with international standards include.
the ability to cooperate cross-border rather than being required to do so.
第二，香港作為成員，of the FSB， is expected to have such a regime.
scope of entities, the right to designate further categories to ensure flexibility.
It is important to note that implementation of such a regime in Hong Kong would not cede sovereignty.
the right to require an in-scope entity to change its structures, but this is subject to hard-wired appeals processes.
跨 border cooperation is key, and would be aided by the fact that most regimes that follow the FSB key attributes will have similar principles, which should assist.
The bill is important to build the framework for resolution regime. Although there is more to be done on a range of issues, for example, bail-in and total loss absorbing capacity.
The important overriding principle is to balance the need for regulators to have the right to act decisively and to have some discretion, against the market having the right to a transparent and certain regime.
和第四ly，香港does not currently have any form of corporate rescue regime， and liquidation as the only tool on insolvency， is overly blunt and will not always be sufficient or appropriate.
在 terms of new resolution powers, for example, interference with property rights, unilateral transfer of assets, bail-in, which wipes out shareholders and creditors, these will also be subject to checks and balances to protect the market.
There are safeguards in the bill so that Hong Kong has the right not to cooperate with other jurisdictions if Hong Kong creditors would be put at a disadvantage, or it results or is likely to result in financial stability for Hong Kong.
第三ly，香港會被落後，如果它不引入such a regime，and regulators in other jurisdictions may recommend their regulated entities not to contract with Hong Kong entities，or if they do，the cost of capital may be higher.
會誒請咧呢個團體代表，如果未有啊提交佢哋嘅書面意見嘅，或者係佢哋有補充嘅意見咧，就請大家係可以提供畀我哋嚇社會人士亦都係一樣嚇。我亦都提醒出席嘅團體代表，你哋嘅意見書喺會。
唔該。
好啊，下一位係誒，Mr. David Alexander。
是 therefore able to provide protection to Hong Kong's interests. Thank you.
So good morning, everyone. Thank you for allowing us to speak at this.
There's also substitution possible. So if one company gets into problems,
Should there be an insolvency, and finally, there is this company liquidation procedures, which was mentioned before.
所以第一樣嘢要講係，係有個好複雜嘅保護機制喺香港，去保護政策持有者。
We think one of the key points about this this new bill is that it should not harm the competitiveness of Hong Kong as an international financial centre, but should be consistent with other markets.
在事件 of insurance companies coming into difficulties， so and that that includes management oversight， fit and proper executives appointed by the firms but vetted by the insurance authority。
And to be honest, I don't think we've seen adequate evidence that a pure insurance company could bring down the whole financial market in Hong Kong. We've not seen that that evidence being put forward, so we would like to see that.
The policyholders can be more easily, either finding the equivalent cover with another institution of insurance, or they could be forcibly migrated more easily. So that interconnectedness and contagion does not exist in the insurance industry.
Independent company audit, the appointed actuary system on the life side, review of reserves on the non-life side, oversight and guidance by the the Office of the Commission of Insurance, solvency capital requirements, additional capital margins above those minimum solvency margins.
Having said that, we do believe that there is space to to add to the resolution regime as proposed in this bill, and we see that it should be a supplement to what's there, not repeating what's there already, and we think it should focus very much on the resolution regime and not other parts.
this group. So let me let me start by saying, the Federation of Insurers represents the insurance industry in Hong Kong, and we do believe that insurance is somewhat different from other financial institutions. I would like to highlight some areas of this bill which we think need to be tailored for the insurance industry.
嗯。
otherwise, there's duplication here.
So, thank you very much for listening to our comments. I'm be happy to take any questions.
公司應該有那種彈性，知道當他們簽約合約時，他們可以依賴那。
with the additional requirements of after deal notifications and adequate time to provide contrary instructions.
and I think also the the issue around contract certainty, contract certainty is an extremely important part of the insurance and reinsurance market that.
first is like the proposed arrangement adequately address the matters of opting out versus opting in of the default investment strategy for existing and new scheme members.
Insisting that a holding company is responsible for its subsidiaries and holding that holding company accountable for that seems to go against limited liability companies.
Paragraph 12 refers to new members and paragraph 13 refers to existing scheme members, who have previously not given any instructions on the choice of CFS prior to the DIS implementations.
下位係香港退休計劃協會馮裕其先生。Thank you, Chairman。啊，HKRSA嚟support the launch of a default investment strategy，但We do have some concerns and suggestions on the bill。
在兩百條十二和條十三，已指明除非或直到基金成員給予具體指示給受託人，受託人將會被法律要求必須投資或轉移所有利益，根據DIS。
所以，realising that we're rather short on time, I'd like to say that also we feel that because insurance is a very specialist sub sub segment of the financial institutions market, we think the insurance authority should have a very very strong role in any resolution of insurance companies.
潛在早期幹預由保險監察官辦，應有問題，以及擬議的保户保護基金，應有問題。有個基金被提出，並經立法程序償還受損客户。
所以going back to my first point, we do feel that insurance is somewhat different from banking and other financial institutions, and in particular, there's strong evidence and global acceptance that some aspects of insurance mean that there's less risk in the insurance market, particularly around contagion and interconnectedness, and we do feel that.
Okay, so I think the some of the things that concern us in this this bill at the moment are things that might damage, I guess what we might say that some of the financial fundamentals or the fundamentals of business and the legal system in in Hong Kong. So, for example, holding
We feel that forced acquisition is is an area where we have some great concern that companies would be attracted to Hong Kong by by knowing that it's an open environment and they would not be saddled by some other company's misfortune. And so, if you take that away, that could harm the competitiveness of Hong Kong.
and my final point is just to go back to an existing point I made at the start, which is around levies that we already have. As I mentioned, the policyholder protection fund being proposed, which will involve some levies of insurance companies to protect policyholders should there be an insolvency. So we see no reason why there should be further levies or collection of money.
但 unless members become more,
assets are transferred under the D.I.S.
佢會 not be in the positions to make choice in their own best interest.
By conducting educational marketing campaign prior to having individuals commit to opting in and opting out.
educate educated about what opt-in or opt-out options entail and what risks are involved.
Repeatedly emphasised the need to empower members by encouraging members' education and active participation in making investment decisions.
There are more not always out of ignorance, who just will not take any actions to make a chance. However, well study or guide, or even for significant amount.
The question remains on the matter of how much time would should pass before the members should deem to have given his/her right to actively refuse the offer default options.
它會被視為犯了錯誤，而所以允許預設選項存在。因此，如何選項被選入或選出變得極為重要。我們都希望這樣的人能做出最寬泛的選擇，無論他的動機。
孟生，孟生，對唔住啊！我我必須要喺度打斷你嘅嘅發言，因為你剛才講嗰啲咧，基本上係我哋另外一條嘅條例草案嘅誒意見嚟嘅。咁因為我哋今日誒討論嘅咧就係金融機構嘅處理機制。
the the word unless and until phases, which is used in the both paragraphs, begs the questions of what might be an appropriate time limit for giving instructions. Secondly, even though paragraph thirteen mentions adequate time, the time period is defined is undefined and can be interpreted differently, regardless.
linked to the above, it is more important questions of whether notions of allowing members sometimes for providing instruction, in or of itself, necessary leads to more informed decision making, which presumably would be a major reasons for considering the time factor. The MPF has replaced.
HKRSA clearly support and enables individuals to better understand and actively choose their retirement investment options. We therefore see the introductions of the DIS as a golden opportunity for both the government and the industry to improve MPF members' knowledge about the proposed change, as well as
這些活動將激勵成員變得更積極地參與決定他們希望將其資產如何投資。透過此舉，MPF 8 亦可幫助減少潛在的投訴，來自不可預見的不利投資結果，因為在獲得書面、知情同意時。
In closing, we would like to suggest what this could be a golden opportunity for MPF A to require that all two point seven million MPF member, not just new or existing default fund members, be notified of the new DIs. That's given everyone a reminder and a chance to rethink his her retirement investment option.
While professionals are well aware that of out and of in carry risks, this may not be apparent as a to lay person, including members who already find current MPF offering too complicated to understand. By embarking on a membership-wide information education committee (REC) campaign, we're bringing the
Thank you.
Good morning.
Mr. Chatha。
implications of the decisions.
There are three key messages we would like to deliver on behalf of the group.
包括條文，對於認可其他管轄區採取的決議行動。
和第三，的，重要性，，of，ongoing，dialogue，and，market，consultation，during，the，rulemaking，process。
嗰個部分啦，好嘛嚇，多謝曬你嚇。噉我哋下一位咧係誒MissJo。
第一，係critical importance of Hong Kong developing a resolution regime which is internationally aligned with other major jurisdictions.
not only has Hong Kong failed to introduce such a regime before the end of 2015 deadline, it's also lagging behind other members of the SFB.
In addition, it's expected that the IMF will use the FSB's assessment methodology in assessments as part of the financial sector assessment programme starting in 2016.
香港是個 premier國際金融中心， hosting 29 of the 30 banks designated by the FSB in November 2015 as being globally systemically important banks.
第二，ly， the need for such a regime to be introduced within the current legislative session in order to ensure that Hong Kong fulfils its overdue obligations as a member of the Financial Stability Board.
這Combined with the requirements of its membership of the FSB and its commitments to the FSB to introduce such a regime before the end of 2015, means that Hong Kong needs to put in place a resolution regime which meets international standards as a matter of urgency.
The group is committed to helping the Bills Committee, the HKMA and the SFC develop an appropriate and proportionate regulatory framework that enhances the stability and liquidity of the Hong Kong financial market and maintains Hong Kong's status as a premier international financial centre.
誒條例草案，你剛才講嘅應該係另外一條M.P.F.嘅嗰個誒條例草案嚟嘅。咁誒，我哋都好歡迎你剛才誒發表咗意見啦。噉我相信咧，你可能係需要另外咧係誒將你嘅意見書咧係畀我哋誒嗰個強積金嘅條例草案。
Thank you to the Bills Committee for inviting us to appear today. We appear on behalf of Asia Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association, or ASIFMA, who represent a significant number of international financial institutions, all of whom are interested stakeholders in the Hong Kong financial markets and are dedicated to Hong Kong's success.
Standards are developed and progressed.
Good morning, Mr. Chairman and honoured members.
Next is Mr. Isabell. Thank, please.
和其負面影響於社會及經濟。
全球金融中心，such as Hong Kong，will therefore be expected to have a satisfactory regime in place before such assessments start.
The association strongly supports the financial institutions resolution bill, as it introduces an effective resolution regime.
reciprocal access and recognition will be key to ensuring that Hong Kong's regulatory framework is consistent with that of other key jurisdictions, so that Hong Kong's financial markets can continue to thrive.
從的視角，of rationalising the regimes to which they are subject，the group is keen to see the implementation of a of a regime in Hong Kong which dovetails with other globally accepted regimes.
The group lends its full support to assist in developing a regulatory regime for Hong Kong that reduces systemic risk and maintains Hong Kong's position as a leading financial centre. Thank you. Thank you.
As Standard Chartered Bank is the chairman bank of the Hong Kong Association this year, I am representing the association. I have also sat on the association's working group on recovery and resolution over the past three years.
金融機構是要求在報報於他們受管的制度，而在一個市場有著大量的存在，而這個市場沒有合適的制度，將會是令監管者在該機構的家鄉和其他受管地區感到嚴重的擔憂。
Accordingly, the failure to introduce a regime which does not meet such required international standards would make Hong Kong uncompetitive internationally and create needlessly onerous requirements for market participants faced with multiple regulatory standards.
In order to achieve international alignment of regulatory regimes, the group strongly supports the development of an appropriate and proportionate scope for Hong Kong's resolution regime, including a recognition regime for equivalent foreign regulatory regimes.
作為Rules on the resolution regimes in many jurisdictions are in the process of development, we urge the HKMA and the SFC to remain flexible and conduct regular market consultations with stakeholders, so that Hong Kong can have the best rules for the continued stability and functioning of its financial markets.
The group are appreciative of the level of consultation which was undertaken prior to the launch of the bill, and are broadly supportive of the proposed regime as it is set out in the bill. They note that the bill contemplates certain rules will be set out in subsidiary legislation enabling alignment of Hong Kong's rules with those of other jurisdictions as needed, and as international.
Following the global financial crisis, international regulators introduced a series of reforms to enhance the resilience and stability of the financial system, strengthen financial institutions' management of capital, financial exposures and key operating functions, and reduce the risk of bank failure.
香港是 regarded as a key international financial centre.
每個決議機制必須滿足一係數關鍵屬性，由FSB要求。
Third, a bank failure undermines confidence in the banking system and the wider economy.
決 resolution 幫助確保穩定和連續性，銀行的關鍵功能對社會和經濟。
The regulations seek to ensure a failing bank can be resolved without resorting to government bailouts using taxpayers' money.
The resolution regime must give national authorities the powers to rapidly bring orderly resolution of a failing financial institution.
香港 hosts branches and subsidiaries of almost all the significantly important global institutions and regional financial institutions.
in particular, members of the association strongly support the bill and sincerely hope the bill will pass through Legco and be enacted into law without delay.
第二， insolvency procedures do not ensure continuity of key banking functions， particularly the public's access to their deposits and access to credit.
金融危機顯示，許多司法管轄區缺乏保護金融系統的法律和監管權力，如果一個系統性重要的金融機構失敗。
和，的銀行可以維持關鍵功能，for the benefit of society and the economy。as such， an effective resolution regime is fundamental to these reforms。
Members of the association strongly support the implementation of an effective resolution regime in Hong Kong, and many of its members have actively participated in the consultation process.
contingент risks from potential shocks originating originating elsewhere in the world can be transmitted swiftly to Hong Kong's financial system, with its relatively substantial contribution to the Hong Kong economy.
The Financial Stability Board was tasked by G20 leaders to develop a robust alternative to publicly funded bank rescues. Hong Kong, as an FSB member, needs to establish a resolution regime.
Normal corporate insolvency procedures are an inadequate remedy for banks for a number of reasons. First, they are initiated at the point of insolvency. The loss of confidence in a bank by its depositors will occur before this point.
香港作為一個國際金融中心， hosts many important global and regional financial institutions. Hong Kong needs to be seen to take prompt action to implement the key attributes, and the bill creates a framework to achieve this.
嗯。
誰 operate here?
Next is Miss Nobred.
從香港到其他 compliant 裁定管轄權。
The bill will retain Hong Kong's competitiveness against rivals such as Singapore.
草擬決議案，故而包含與FSB一致的條款。
The bill will help contain any such risks, including the moral hazard of public rescue of financial institutions.
key attributes and also you know covers a number of of areas that institutions like ourselves think are very important within this.
一個有效的解決機制將也會補充其他採納的規例，以強化本地金融體係的韌性，例如更高的資本要求。
We we see these provisions as very strong as something that will work well in a framework to allow cooperation with other regimes elsewhere, which should be in the interest of Hong Kong's financial stability.
所以，協會完全支持該法案，我們注意到仍有一些點需要在指引和規則中涵蓋，由監管機構設定，我們期待與他們合作完成這些諮詢。謝謝。
As others have mentioned, there will be a number of provisions which will need further detailed elaboration by the sectoral regulators in their role as resolution authorities, and we think that's the right way to approach things. So, as the draft bill is proposed, it provides a very good framework for that.
The FSB expects all major host jurisdictions, including Hong Kong, to establish resolution regimes to support the resolution of globally significant financial institutions. Failure to do so, at worst, could result in large, systemically important banks moving their Asian hubs from.
Thank you. So I'm here this morning representing Deutsche Bank. Part of the reason that we are doing this is that we are very supportive of the bill and the way it has been drafted, and we wanted to express that support to the committee. We have been very engaged with all authorities as they're developing resolution regimes from the FSB at global level.
placing in place the key attributes, and then a number of authorities and policymakers around the world, and in particular in Hong Kong over the last two to three years as the regime has been developed, we think there has been a very good and thorough consultation process between the FSTB, the HKMA and SFC and other authorities to develop a.
I think we don't have a lot of significant points to raise on it. But one thing that I would like to emphasise is in particular the cross border provisions and the way that those are drafted. We recognising you know what others have said already about Hong Kong's role as an international financial centre and that this is an important thing for international organisations.
Next is Mr. Miller.
Thank you. Thank you.
係，係，係。
所以，我認為那那係非常重要嘅。
一，something that the international community is is forcing on Hong Kong.
Good morning, Mr. Chairman, honoured members. I'm speaking on behalf of the leading global law firm Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer, where I head the financial services regulatory practice in Asia.
What would happen if it becomes non-viable? So, how globally its material subsidiaries, its material operations that are critical would would be able to continue to operate if it becomes non-viable?
We've been leading advisers on too big to fail issues and resolution plans globally, including helping some of the Hong Kong institutions with their recovery plans and working also on the consultations.
We've just recently celebrated our 30th anniversary in Hong Kong. We strongly support the bill, and we've made a written submission which I I would urge you to to read. I'm not going to go through the the entire written submission, but
consistent features, and that also they are put in place quickly, so that authorities can look at these and understand how they will impact on individual institutions, and also how the frameworks and legislation will work together.
I think in summary, you know, we are we are very supportive of what has been put forward. We would like to see this put in place as quickly as possible, and we will continue to to work with the authorities in Hong Kong and in other jurisdictions as they develop the detailed secondary legislation to to underpin this.
Because the orderly resolution coordination between different jurisdictions is what will help emphasise that. But we see that there is a good balance with the authorities having to meet certain conditions, recognising what is in Hong Kong's best interests, and therefore they're well balanced provisions that make sense. So we think that.
I also think that, in addition, compared to what others have said in terms of the need to push this legislation forward and get this enacted as soon as possible, is something that we would support as well. There's definitely been a lot of activity over the last number of years in various jurisdictions to put in place regimes. It is important that they have.
In that we provide background on the global governmental and regulatory consensus that all key financial centres have have reached to put in place resolution powers similar to those that are in the bill. We've also explained how the bill is extremely important for Hong Kong locally and is not just.
finally, and this is the point that I'd like to cover here, we've included in the submission two written hypotheticals. They're hypothetical situations about banks, what would happen to them if the bill does not go through in in different scenarios, and and then what, how that would likely change if the
restructure around those.
市區、Areas和Branches。
然後。
Big operations in Hong Kong, and the resolution powers aren't there.
If the resolution powers are in place, here's how it is more likely to to play out.
所以，如果如果沒有解決權力在 place，，這裡是怎麼，我認為是可能要演繹出來。
That same bank has subsidiaries in Hong Kong and a branch in Hong Kong.
The second hypothetical, which I don't have time to go through, is a little bit different. It's about a Hong Kong headquartered entity.
Are supposed to be, we have confidence that Hong Kong could play its role. We don't need to move things out of Hong Kong.
The headquarters regulator looks at how this resolution plan will work out globally, in all the key jurisdictions where the the group operates, including Hong Kong.
Bill is enacted promptly. The first scenario, and I'll be brief here. The first scenario is as follows: There's a global financial institution headquartered in Europe, and it has a resolution authority in its home jurisdiction there. The resolution authority there requires it to put together a resolution plan that covers.
This same resolution plan has at the headquarters level plans to bail in liabilities and to transfer some key operations of a big European bank that's a subsidiary of it into a bridge bank, so that the the activities can be run in the bridge bank for a period pending wind down or sale to other banks.
所以那係背景， to look whether the resolution plan will work. So if if the bill is not in place, here is how it would play out. And and I confess this is not a complete hypothetical. Global banks are already looking at what resolution powers are in place in the key jurisdictions where they operate, and are looking at whether and how they would need to.
The host, the home country resolution authority would say, well look, we have these material operations in Hong Kong, we need those critical functions to be able to transfer to a bridge bank, we need to make sure that the bail-in is recognised, but there aren't any powers to do this in Hong Kong. The authorities there don't have powers.
to do this, so we either need to downsize what we do in Hong Kong, or shut it down, or move it to another another jurisdiction, maybe another Asia Pac jurisdiction that does have these powers in place, because we just can't afford to have our global group not be resolvable, because we have
the the headquarters regulator says oh there is a mechanism for recognition recognition of bail-in and there is a recognition of of transfer to a bridge bank it's not automatic the authorities in Hong Kong have to look at what protections apply to Hong Kong make sure it makes sense for Hong Kong but it could work and that's what the global standards.
and looking at the subsidiaries overseas of the Hong Kong entity and the branches overseas of the Hong Kong entity, and the resolution authorities in the other countries will look at does the headquarters entity have adequate resolution powers? Because there will be key functions, critical functions in the countries all around the world where Hong Kong entities have sub.
一個初步嘅回應啊！
嗯，Thank you, Chairman.
所以，我諗我stop here。Thank you, Ms. Chairman。Thank you。
In this session, because there are other jurisdictions also looking to Hong Kong as an IFC, to make sure that we have a proper regime, appropriate and proportionate in place.
Think should we move out of Hong Kong? Again, these are hypotheticals, but they are things that our our global clients and and and other large banks are already thinking about. Thank you.
And if if the resolution powers aren't in place at headquarters, the the host countries will be nervous and they will either shut those down or they'll move them into subsidiaries that they can regulate locally, put in place bail-in locally under local laws and parcel up the whole group, make it much less efficient and potentially make these institutions.
We are grateful for all the comments made both here in the presence of this committee and also in the written submissions. Actually, we recognise that there is a consistent and overall support and strong support for timely implementation of the bill. And several representations mentioned that there should be an
on some of the comments that made, I think there are several references to the importance of cross-border resolution and the importance to strike a balance between protecting Hong Kong's interests and also performing Hong Kong's obligations as an international financial centre. I think it was quite rightly pointed out.
that the Hong Kong is not required to implement automatically cross-border actions overseas, but we would have discretion to make sure that we we see to it that there are trigger trigger criteria in Hong Kong. Like there there are if there were disadvantages for Hong Kong affecting Hong Kong's local interest, or if the rest
Such action is not in Hong Kong's is not in the interests of Hong Kong's financial stability. We will not be automatically recognise such actions. And on the there were several references to the actually the framework being proposed in the in the bill here. It needs to
be supplemented by rulemaking and there are there's a considerable volume of rules to be made and actually quite a few of the details of the regime they are still work in progress in the international arena. We fully recognise that and that is why when we do the rulemaking we will fully we will be consulting fully the
industry and also look at the international developments to make sure that Hong Kong is not left out, nor are we sort of leaping ahead ahead of the international consensus. Finally, Mr. Chairman, the insurance sector mentioned their concern about the difference between the insurance sector and the banking sector. This is a point we fully recognise, even.
在金融穩定委員會 deliberation， it is recognised that in terms of connectedness， interconnectedness and in terms of contagion， the the insurance sectors are quite different from the so-called traditional concept of a banking financial institutions. But the FSB actually key attributes they specific。
嗯。
好，James。
誒，梁繼昌嘅。
誒，政府有冇？
如果《解僱條款》條例被通過喺香港，
Thank you, Chairman. I I got two very general questions. First.
啊，謝謝議員。啊，the in terms of the啊，
with the company and who, in fact, have the final say.
Is that correct? And I want to ask the delegation: Is that the? Is my understanding correct? And are you willing to do so?
Simply say recognise that an insurance could be systemically important. So we are not suggesting that. This is a point I also made in the last meeting that the inclusion of financial insurance, like eight of the nine chief SII's in Hong Kong, it does not automatically mean that resolution action will be taken necessarily automatically. But there
There will be the checking of the three criteria, and the general assumption remains that the traditional insurance activities, they are when they are no longer viable and they have systemic impact on Hong Kong, that is when we will take resolution action. It is not by virtue of the inclusion that would necessarily require resolution on each and every count.
How flexible do we have? I mean, in order, for example, if a foreign jurisdiction implement a resolution regime, as the the the permanent the secretary has mentioned that we we do have say, if the resolution regime is not advantageous.
到香港，我們有選擇不跟從決議機制。我的兩個問題是：當你説不優勢，你實際上是什麼意思？這會不會影響到整個地區的經濟、行業或公司或集團？
That is my first question, and my other question is, who has the final say whether to implement the resolution regime? You know, promoted by by by foreign jurisdiction is that the resolu the resolution authority or resolution authority in consultation.
My other questions refers to the funding of the regime. I suppose in all sectors, the banks, the insurers or the other securities company would have to fund the non-viable peer.
The recognition of cross-border resolution actions, the the the discretion actually the decision power rests with the Hong Kong resolution authority solely. But then there are actually criteria in the bill, as I mentioned just now, so I won't repeat them.
Of course, the the research authority when they deliberate on on the matter, they would be actually also be consulting with the company. That they would be looking at the situation of company, because there there is the the first criteria is that it will have to be manifestly the case that the insure the.
financial institution is not viable or is likely to be non-viable. Now, of course, actually in some of the submissions, there were suggestions of actually there should be clearer criteria or specific trigger mechanism. Now, I think the the the member Mr. Leong mentioned actually, actually, I mean you touched on a point.
或The other viable peers is is that correct? And and what is the view of the industry as a whole? I think are they agreeable to this type of funding mechanism? Can you be more explicit, Mr. Secretary?
although we do see that there are submissions indicating that there should be no ground for such levy because of the existence of the other PPF or the
from the financial institution under scope of the particular sector, the outgoings or the funds which were expended by the by the restoration authority in meeting the restoration of that particular case. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
There may not be hard and fast trigger mechanism on under what circumstances criterion one would be trigger or criterion three would be trigger. But in the drawing up of the detailed guidance notes, we will be illustrating more on how this is done. And if I address the other point that the
and that that is it is a matter of judgement on how to arrive at the view that an institution is not viable or unlikely to viable. we our intention is that we would be in the in the guidance notes we would be coming up with illustrative examples to to to to illustrate how such a deliberate
Would be done. The the second, the other criteria in in our bill, which is the third criterion, is that the the that the failure of the particular case or the non-validity of the particular FI will have to be having a systemic impact on Hong Kong.
impact on the systemic financial stability of Hong Kong, and it could be affecting initially the the financial stability, and there is also possible impact on the wider economy as a whole. Now, as I said just now.
Mr. Long mentioned, and that is regard to the funding of the resolution actions. Now, actually, there was the HKFI. Mr. Alexander also mentioned the what they in their case is policyholders protection fund. Now, there are similar funds in the other financial sectors, but they are like the policyholders fund.
That is intended for for compensating the policyholders in the case of the insurance sector. So if there should be failure of the insurance a particular insurance company, that PPF is intended to compensate the policyholders. But it is not intended for for what we call the
addressing the question of public funds, if need be, injected temporarily or initially to fund the resolution actions. So that that injection and so forth won't be covered by the PPF. So there's a need for subsequent recovery, and this is why.
The investors compensation fund or the deposit insurance, those serve different purposes. So we still need a separate levy mechanism in order. And in Hong Kong, we actually have already tried to strike a balance between the need for ex ante funding and exposed funding and desirability of ex ante funding, which actually would would would require.
到半，是那，是那正確。
Mr. David Alexander.
widely to say all members of of a particular financial industry, so in our case, ah.
take a view on the on the final mechanism and the final recovery proportionality. Thank you, Chairman. 好，郭榮亨議。
Yes, Mr. Chairman. Actually, I would like to invite Mr. Chan from the Office of Commission of Insurance to address this particular point. Mr. Chan.
That for Hong Kong to meet the KAs, the key attributes, contractual override may be a necessary power.
The liability to repay those claims was spread amongst the whole global insurance and reinsurance industry, and if one part of that is not, I guess, not certain, then there's some concern about whether the the money could actually find its way to the right place at the right time.
risk around the world that insurance companies rely on the fact that major major incidents will not happen in many jurisdictions all at the same time. So, for example, Tohoku earthquake in Japan, the
Actually upfront levy from the financial institutions. We we we also explained last time that actually we have our choice for the administration is that we recommend to the legislature that we would go for an exposed funding as as an exposed recovery in order to recover from the
Mr. Chairman, before I continue, I have to make a declaration because I'm actually a senior consultant to one of the deputation. Cliff Chance, Mr. Chairman, I forgot to make a declaration. I'm sorry about this. My other question is the funding of the resolution regime. It will not touch on any public money. Is that correct? I mean, it would be funded by.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I think I will address this point first. In our consultation paper one and two, we did actually present to the industry the various options of the funding mechanism, and and of course there is a range of views expressed on.
how they they regard the sort of the the appropriateness of the mechanism, we also explained actually how we also have regard to the international practice or the approach adopted in other major jurisdictions, and there are actually also exempted and exposed.
approach as to the the scope of the recovery. We also had a discussion in our consultation paper on whether it should be a restricted as we today as we propose to be the those so-called within scope financial institutions of that particular sector, or it should be extended more wide.
When we aim to strike a balance between a very embracing approach or more specific approach, which relates to the the sector, the financial institution financial institution under coverage in the resolution regime, we we took the view, and as we explained in our consultation paper, we actually are.
Our third paper, CB三，which was issued just a few months, actually late last year, we explained how we arrived at this particular approach. And and actually the levy mechanism, one important aspect of the levy mechanism, is that when at the end, so at the end of the resolution, when when
線可以被drawn， and there is recovery to be made. The rescue authority will be making recommendations to the financial secretary， and the financial secretary will be taking a broad look at the appropriateness of the recommendation. And actually， that particular levy mechanism or levy recovery.
Approach will be presented to the Legislative Council for consideration and approval before implementation. So we believe that this is an appropriate way to safeguard the the the need to avoid dipping the public purse, and at the same time allows the public represented here in the legislature to to
the
Mr. Miller.
are really around the issues that I described.
and because of that pressure, there'll be pressure on them to try to
Would the resolution strategy work in the key jurisdictions where they operate?
also don't want to be in a position where their taxpayers would have to bail out a group.
overarching issues that headquarters resolution authorities are thinking through with the large large institutions, the ones that we're involved in at least.
to to support things around the world to keep things running because pieces of the group are in jurisdictions where the international consensus on resolution standards has not been adopted.
Some follow-up the the rules-making power by by the offer, and this will be follow from the internet in international standards, and also will fully consult the industry before we we we fully implement the rules subsequently.
Thank you, Chairman. I've got a question for Mr. David Alexander. You mentioned earlier that there will be contractual uncertainties as a result of the passage of this bill, and that the insurance industry is worried about that. Can you be more specific about your concerns? That's my first question.
So I think the the issue there is that in in the resolution mechanism, it says that the the authorities have the ability to alter contracts or in effect void contracts in the situation they deem appropriate. So the whole idea of the insurance industry is a very large.
sharing of risk amongst the population through insurance companies. So if one part of that mechanism cannot be relied on in exceptional circumstances, then there's some lack of confidence in the whole mechanism of risk sharing. And I understand that that would apply to many other industries as well.
所以，如果如果它要會在這條法案內，那它需要被考慮得非常非常仔細，和在例外的情況下，和有極大的透明度。如果將會有一些合同的覆蓋，所以有某些關心這件事，和關心與多樣化有關。
Thank you. If you can suggest ways in which the bill could be improved in order to cater for the concerns which you've mentioned, especially from the perspective of the insurance industry, we would welcome to see those suggestions. But at the same time, I'm sure the under secretary would tell you.
Okay, thank you. Yes, this is one of the key HPI requirements that the LA should have. The resolution authority should have the right to revise the contract. So, but in in our bill we have we have this sort of power under the LA. But this this the detail will will be followed by a.
Thank you. So, as I said, we welcome any specific suggestions as to ways in which you you you think the bill could be improved. My second question is for Mr. Miller. Thank you for your submissions and also your paper, which I've read. You mentioned there are certain scenarios which international financial institutions are already thinking of.
And are you saying that those scenarios could now be addressed? My understanding it could be better addressed with the passage of this bill, right? But are there scenarios which you think the present bill is inadequate, but could be improved upon by by way of amendments or changes to the bill?
And they will look at the what businesses are in each jurisdiction, what cross-border businesses are being done, and what would happen in a meltdown. Really, if they if they put put it into resolution, whether these whether the resolution actions could be carried out in the.
啊！
我，誒。
That still have to be.
There's not an international consensus yet on some of the key areas, like, like.
The approach that we are adopting is that we're linking the misconduct in question.
Nobody's talked about total loss of foreign capacity and TLAC, but that's developing as we go along.
There is no such linkage in their approach, so all they need to prove is.
and consult on it and do it in a sensible way, but frankly history has shown that that's that's the way things do normally happen here, so I'm I'm not overly concerned about that.
分析緊The approach in four different jurisdictions. Now, my question is this: It seems like in the overall comparison between Hong Kong, UK, the US and Singapore.
When other jurisdiction don't necessarily need that linkage between the falling of the financial institution and the act in question, do you think we should adopt that approach in Hong Kong?
Together with whether it has materially contributed to the falling of the financial institution. Now we discussed this last time, but if you look at the approach of the UK and perhaps Singapore.
But the way the bill is set up, there will be rulemaking power with consultation. Everybody said there will be consultation to develop those, so that it's done in step with the global developments later on.
In question, and the falling of the financial institution. Now, I don't think that's the middle. In your paper, you describe this the Hong Kong approach as the middle way. I'm not convinced, frankly. I think
jurisdictions and what would happen locally also, and that's where the sorry I don't have any clients yet who are saying we have to leave Hong Kong at all. They're saying, oh, it's great that Hong Kong is actively pursuing putting in place resolution powers and they're watching the space and and that so that's.
That's not that's not shouldn't have been an alarming comment, but if it doesn't if the bill doesn't go through and Hong Kong decides we don't need these resolution powers, we're going to delay even, that would be more alarming. And and really I think I think the background to this is the headquarters politicians.
Move the group around, restructure things in the group to to avoid that issue where the legal the legal system isn't following the global standards. And then and then on the what could be improved, I think as has been recognised in in in in several things that have been said this morning, there are key areas.
I think that's the right approach. Actually, I don't think it makes sense to try to hardwire something in now in Hong Kong when there's not an international consensus as to how it should work. Hong Kong, before they just they shouldn't even later just adopt the international consensus wholesale because the international consensus is reached. They should think about how it works in Hong Kong.
O.K. 啊，主席，我可唔可以問到一條問題？好啊，你問啦。啊，Thank you for the response from the administration. 啊，regarding the questions we put up last time. 啊，there is a question that which I put. 啊，in relation to the clawback of the remuneration. And I see that the administration has helpfully put together a table.
That employee has been misbehaving, or there is a material error, or material failure of risk management, or in Singapore that there has been a failure to discharge the duties of his office, or that there has been breach of trust, etc. So there is no necessary linkage between the act or omission.
嗯。
所以。
喺。
呃。
Miss Kim， you can answer the question.
喺Miss Chan未答之前，我想問問同事咧，誒對於今朝嘅誒團體代表誒嚟表達意見，大家仲有冇其他啲問題想同佢哋誒交換嘅？
冇係咪？OK，噉我要喺度咧，係多謝咁多位團體代表咧出席今朝嘅會議啊，因為我知道大家都忙，咁所以你哋啊可以喺誒呢個時候咧係退席嘅，好嘛？啊，多謝你哋嚇，多謝曬。
We were very much in the realm of a bill that is addressing resolution and issues that cause a financial institution to fail. That the clawback within this bill should relate to to that activity. And so balancing various
Sorry. So your observation is correct that we have sought to link the clawback mechanism to contribution to non-viability. The key attributes talk about a responsible person, and they are talking about a responsible person in terms of non-viability of a financial.
institution leading to resolutions, so we have followed that route, which I think is more similar to the United States route. As we discussed last time, in the UK, they're talking about their general clawback rules, where they they set rules for the for the institutions themselves, and the institutions themselves in setting up their remuneration.
Policies have to provide for clawback, and we have a similar sort of expectation which we talked about last time. That's in our supervisory policy manual, where we talk about what the institutions themselves should do in terms of setting up their remuneration policy so it doesn't incentivise excessive risk-taking. But we thought that as
Factors in terms of the the scope of the the clawback, who should be within its scope, the the whether it's fixed and variable remuneration, how long it should, the relation back period, if you like, we came out with three plus three fixed and variable, but linked very much towards.
Something that is the subject matter of this bill, which is causing an institution to become non-viable. Can I just ask, how proactive is the HKMA in looking into the remunerative systems of each of the banks that are operating in Hong Kong, especially the investment banks?
Do you ask them to give you the whole design of their bonus and remuneration packages, and to see whether that system is safe enough, or that does it encourage excessive risk taking? Is there a plan to step up that approach as a result of the passage of this bill? Is there any plan?
I haven't discussed with my supervisory colleagues whether there will be a step up as a result of this bill. I know that back in two thousand and eight, two thousand and nine, when the Financial Stability Board came out with its principles for sound remuneration practices, and at the time we produced the SPM module.
好。
呃。
誒，大家同事對於呢一份文件有冇咩誒特別嘅問題、嘅意見？
誒，政府方面有冇需要做一啲補充？冇其他補充係咪？
誒，我記得上一次咧嘅會議，就我哋本嚟有兩個PowerPoint。
誒要同大家介紹嘅，噉我哋淨係做咗一個，咁而家咧就不如請我哋誒金管局啊。
The importance of the timing of the enactment has already been discussed both here and at the previous meeting on 5 January, so I won't repeat that discussion.
In terms of overall structure, the FIRB runs to 239 clauses, divided into 15 parts with nine schedules.
誒簡小姐咧係做一個誒簡介，好嘛？就住呢一個條例草案嗰個方面咧，係做一個概述，好嘛？唔該你。
As we've heard today, and Mr Lau explained previously, the FIRB has been designed to implement the FSB's key attributes, and they're the prevailing international standards for resolution regimes.
嗱，同時誒，我哋而家處理嘅呢一份文件咧，就係一誒C B一四四三一五一六零三號文件，咁咧就誒。
yet to to FIRB, mostly I think because again in FIRB you're going to look for behaviour that somehow contributes to to failure, so we're looking a further down a way further down the road on that.
During the course of on-site examinations, etc., supervisors will look into this as part of the overall governance of the institution. Because obviously, from a risk management perspective, it was made clear in the crisis that a wrongly aligned bonus system can jeopardise prudent risk management.
所以它被視為是整個監督機制的一部分，而我們也如我們在提交中所説，將會流經監督行動，如果薪金方案被認為不健全或不謹慎，但我必須説，我們沒有將
Thank, thank you very much, Chairman. So the purpose of this presentation, and I confess it was originally designed to complement the presentation given by Mr Lau on the on the five th of January. But overall, what we're trying to do here is just to map out the the structure of the bill to provide a foundation for discussions to follow. So.
和關鍵屬性 require a dedicated administrative authority to be responsible for exercising the resolution powers, and so the FIB appoints the three sectoral regulators as the resolution authorities for their respective regulated constituencies, and that that's done in clause two of the bill, where resolution authority is is defined.
in expertise as required.
但那並不必然意味著他們將會透過該機制的權力來解決。
Licensing criteria, and as a consequence of that, removal of the licence is warranted.
它後續釐清了主決議權力與其他決議權力之間的關係，在第九條。
And where a lead resolution authority is designated for a cross-sector group, only the lead resolution authority can initiate resolution of the institutions within the group.
the the next few parts of the FIRB focus on the sequence of resolution, beginning in Part Three Division One with the powers necessary to prepare for resolution.
to protect deposits, insurance policies and client assets to no less an extent than they would be protected on a winding up, and subject to all of that, to seek to contain the costs of resolution and in so doing protect public money.
這些， together with clause 26, which enables the resolution authority to consider the impact of its resolution actions on the financial stability of other jurisdictions, reflect the requisite objectives and functions of the regime as set out in the key attributes.
Now clause nine, as I mentioned, sets out the lead resolution authority's role. So whilst the lead resolution authority coordinates a group resolution, it can, if need be, give a direction to another resolution authority or take an action itself to ensure that something is done.
所以，Part One of the bill deals in Clause Two with the terms used, and importantly, it's in the definitions that the scope of application of the resolution regime is set, through the definition of a within scope financial institution as a banking sector entity, an insurance sector entity, or a securities and futures.
Sector entity, and as Mr Lau mentioned earlier, when the deputations were here, the aim is to implement Key Attribute 1.1 by capturing any financial institution that could be systemically significant or critical if it fails. So, if they could be systemically critical, we want them to be within the scope of the.
Clause five of the FRB defines when an FI ceases to be viable, and this is relevant for the first of the three conjunctive conditions for resolution, which is that a within scope FI has ceased or is likely to cease to be viable. And basically, for a regulated institution, non-viability is when they contravene their.
Clause six is the power which Mr. Lau described at our last meeting, allowing the financial secretary to designate other financial institutions or a recognised exchange company, so or a stock exchange, and thus bring them within the scope of the regime if they are considered to pose a systemic risk in the future.
和條七是重要，因為FIRB委任三個跨部門決議機制，在提供財政部長指定其中一個為跨部門決議機制的主導決議機制。這有助於有序決議機制，並反映關鍵屬性。FIRB
the resolution objectives.
和條17提供上訴權，至特別成立的可解決性審裁庭。
Concepts of the key attributes that resolution is for use with institutions which pose a systemic threat at the time of their failure.
Now, as a financial institution moves closer to the point of becoming non-viable, so the activity levels of the resolution authority in preparing for possible resolution will increase.
The resolution authority needs to conduct a resolvability assessment of an FI to determine if there are significant impediments to resolution, and this is covered in clause twelve.
所以，for example，the resolution authority might seek to use this power if a director were to intentionally seek to obstruct a resolution authority's preparations for resolution.
Division two of Part three of the FIRB becomes operable when conditions one and three are fulfilled. So the FI is or is likely to become non-viable and is assessed to be systemic.
To be able to practically apply the resolution tools, a degree of advanced planning is required, and this should hopefully take place very much when a financial institution is in business as usual mode and not under stress.
所以，例如，一個方向可能被 warranted，如果如果董事會的金融機構正在採取行動，可能會威脅到機構的業務轉移給一個已識別的買家。
at the last meeting, and depending on the tools chosen, successful application, particularly of bail-in, may rely on there being sufficient loss-absorbing capacity in some form pre-positioned in specific locations in in the group.
And so to accommodate ongoing international work on this, clause 19 of the FIRB provides a rulemaking power for resolution authority to prescribe loss-absorbing capacity requirements, and that's the TLAC requirements that some of the members of the delegations referred to earlier.
所以，Part Two of the FIRB begins by setting the resolution objectives, which will guide the resolution authorities and to which they must have regard in performing their functions. And to recap, those objectives are to promote financial system stability, including the all-important continuity of critical financial services.
Clause 10 recognises that a resolution authority may need to engage other people with specific types of expertise to assist the RA in performing its functions, and given that resolution is hopefully an extremely rare event, it may not be economic to maintain very large resolution units. And hence, an alternative is to allow the resolution authority to bring
If impediments are found, the resolution authority can require their removal. Clause 14 covers this, but because this is intrusive and can occur when a business is perfectly healthy and resolution is not in sight, there need to be safeguards. And here, clause 15 provides for a financial institution to be given the opportunity to make represent.
現在，一般而言，決議權力將會致力於 devise 一個策略，以處理決議一個金融機構，並制定一個計劃來實施這個策略。而第十三條規定此。這個策略和計劃將涉及識別優先決議工具，即穩定選項，由先生描述。
從The delegations focus on the rules for these protected arrangements.
where resolution involves a transfer to a bridge institution or an AMV owned by the government.
finally, in Division One of Part Five, some provision is made in clauses 76 to 78 for a time-limited deferral of licensing conditions.
所以，如果那些 instrument 傳已經不是已經被寫入或轉換，under the banking capital rules，the resolution authority 可以做，before applying a resolution tool。
And those options, together with the matters necessary for their operation, are set out in the FIRB from clause 33 to clause 73.
Clause 29 extends to an affiliated operational entity, where that entity provides services which are needed to support critical financial activities.
金融機構 under the same holding company, or there are operational difficulties in applying the resolution tools at the operating company financial institution level.
但係，為咗唔要打亂競爭對象太過，和到激勵快速處理一座橋或AMV，延遲係限於12個月。
Resolution is achieved by applying one or more of the five stabilisation options, and Mr Lau showed a diagram of those options at the last meeting.
Before initiating resolution, clause 27 requires the resolution authority to consult the financial secretary as a check and a balance, given the financial secretary's broader view of the financial system and the economy.
The options are applied through the issuance of instruments by the resolution authority, Part Five instruments in FIRB terminology, and they could take the form of a share transfer instrument, a property transfer instrument, or a bail-in instrument.
作為進一步的check and balance，under clause 30，a resolution authority must issue a letter of mindedness to an entity before initiating resolution，and allow the entity a reasonable time，obviously depending on the circumstances and urgency of the case，to to make representations。
Clause 22 empowers the resolution authority in those circumstances to give directions to a financial institution, its group companies and their respective directors and senior management to take or refrain from taking specified actions. But directions can only be given if the resolution authority considers it will assist in meeting the resolution objective.
similarly, when conditions one and three are met and the financial institution is close to resolution, clause 24 empowers a resolution authority to revoke a person's appointment as a director or as the CEO of the financial institution or its holding company, where the resolution authority considers this will assist in meeting.
Part four of the FIRB moves on to resolution proper, and clause 25 sets out the three conjunctive trigger conditions. Broadly, conditions one and two provide that resolution should be triggered when the firm is no longer viable or likely to be no longer viable, and has no reasonable prospect of becoming so. And condition three reflects the cons.
為確保 orderly resolution，the scope of the regime needs to extend to holding companies and affiliated operational entities of within scope financial institutions in certain circumstances. Accordingly, clause 28 empowers a resolution authority to resolve a holding company, and this could be necessary say where there were two highly interconnected.
Clause 31 of the FIB is a somewhat specialised provision focused on the Basel III capital instruments issued by authorised institutions, and these instruments are required by the banking capital rules to contain write-off or conversion clauses if the authorised institution reaches the point of non-viability.
係。
continuity.
和履行義務，
Related but arguably more important provision is found in clause ninety.
所以，after resolution， comes the question of compensation.
是那係essential to the continued performance by the acquirer of critical financial functions in Hong Kong.
和Part Six of the bill contains the FIRB's principal safeguard, the no creditor worse off than on liquidation, or the NICWAL compensation regime.
和的concept是，that no shareholder or creditor should be worse off because of resolution than they would have been if the institution had gone into liquidation immediately before resolution was initiated， and this principle is laid out in clause 102.
但given that resolution is focused on continuity of service, this provision may only be of limited utility. Although the key attributes say that it should be provided, and before using it, the resolution authority would have to consider very carefully its impact on financial markets.
There are certain types of financial arrangements, such as netting and set-off arrangements, which are specifically constructed to protect the parties in the event that one of them fails. And it's important for certainty in the market that the protective economic effect of these arrangements is preserved on resolution. And generally speaking, these
這些安排有兩條，如果決議權力要分開這兩條，保護效果會喪失。所以條文七十五條文規定，財政部會發出規則。
所以，securing orderly resolution and the continuity of critical financial functions may in turn require a continued inward provision of the services which enable those functions to be undertaken. And this is the subject matter of Division Two of Part Five of the FIRB. So, Clause Seventy Nine.
focuses on when a business has been transferred out of the FI in resolution to a purchaser, a bridge or an AMV, and the clause empowers the resolution authority to require the residual FI from which the transfer has been made to require that FI to provide to the acquirer on reasonable commercial terms services.
and in like vein, clause 81 provides the resolution authority with a power to require an affiliated operational entity to continue to provide essential services to a financial institution in resolution or to a purchaser of any part of the financial institution's business, on the same existing terms or on reasonable commercial terms.
所以 divisions three and four of Part five are designed to support the application of the stabilisation options by providing a short two business day breathing space for the resolution authority once resolution is initiated, allowing but not requiring the resolution authority under Clause 83 to suspend payment.
Obviously, it would be difficult to maintain continuity of services if, as a result of an entity going into resolution, all or most of its contractual counterparties abruptly closed out and terminated their contracts with the entity. So, clause nine provides for a resolution authority to be able to suspend for no more than two business days.
At this stage.
deal with this aspect.
跌勢， of an entity is ongoing.
valuation in the claims process is set out in clause 105.
The clawback period extends to three years prior to the start of resolution, but the court can extend by a further three-year period in cases of dishonesty.
在考慮是否要頒發扣款令時，法院必須考慮到該官員貢獻於該金融機構非可持續性的程度，以及該官員的財務狀況，盡可能。
specified conditions must be met before disclosure can be deferred, and the pre-resolution deferral lasts for up to 72 hours. But this may be extended provided the conditions continue to be met.
And if shareholders or creditors are aggrieved by the independent valuer's decision, then clause 107 provides for them to appeal to the specially constituted tribunal, the Resolution Compensation Tribunal.
The key attributes provide for temporary exemptions from disclosure requirements or a postponement of disclosures under listing rules and the like, where disclosure could affect the successful implementation of resolution.
And Part Eight of the FIRB provides the court-based mechanism for this process. So under Clause 144, clawback can be ordered against both fixed and variable remuneration from directors, senior managers and key risk takers in financial institution.
Clause 150 is a complementary provision to clause 148, permitting a resolution authority to direct an exchange to suspend dealings, or alternatively not to suspend dealings, once a temporary deferral of disclosure is initiated under clause 148.
作為我們在上次會議和今天早些時候討論過的，雖然不直接與確保服務連續性有關，當金融機構失敗時，關鍵特徵是決議機構應有權力從負責人身上收回資金，包括剝奪可變報酬。
一 party's termination right against the entity in resolution or a member of its group, provided that all substantive obligations, including payment and delivery obligations, continue to be performed. So this contained stay provides a limited breathing space whilst preserving.
Now there could be problems in enforcing this limited stay if a contract is governed by the law of a jurisdiction other than Hong Kong, and hence Clause 92 provides a rule-making power by which a resolution authority can require contracts to include provisions by which the the counterparties recognise and agree to the.
Now, obviously, it's important that the assessment or valuation of the treatment that shareholders and creditors actually received in resolution, and would hypothetically have received in liquidation, is carried out independently of the resolution authority by a suitably qualified person. And clauses ninety-five, ninety-six, ninety-eight and ninety-nine.
Clause 103 sets out what the independent valuer must do and the assumptions and presumptions to be applied in his valuation, and some of these assumptions are set out in Schedule 7 to the FIRB, and others can be set out in regulations. and The power for the Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury to make those regulations relating to
Part seven of the FIRB provides for the establishment of both the Resolution Compensation Tribunal and the Resolvability Review Tribunal, and these provisions and the procedural mechanics in Schedule 9 are relatively more standard than other parts of the bill and will likely be familiar to members. So I don't propose to go through them clause by clause.
所以這又是另一個設計來支持決議的措施，而這是在FIRB的第9部分，其中第148和149條款處理決議前的期間，當決議很可能發生時，而第151條款處理決議進行中的情況，以及決議的基礎。
係。
獨立評估人。
Resolution objectives and does not prejudice local creditors and shareholders vis-à-vis their counterparts overseas.
可以 require the production of records and documents, and the attendance of persons who can answer questions relevant to a matter under investigation.
和最終税率將由立法會決議實施，如第180條所 envisaged。
And if any resolution funding provided from public funds has not been repaid, clause 178 provides for the imposition of the sector-specific levy on the relevant sectors of the financial industry.
預 funding， 特別是 the provision of liquidity， to be provided from public funds in order to maintain essential functions， as the usual funding markets may initially be closed to an entity in resolution for reasons of lack of confidence and the like。
Clause 176 requires the resolution authority to have regard to the extent to which the failing FI's own resources, including the write-off or conversion of its liabilities, can be used to fund resolution, and sets out the purposes for which resolution funding can be used.
Part ten of the FIRB also supports resolution by providing the resolution authority with powers to obtain information from within-scope financial institutions and their group members, which is reasonably required for the performance of the resolution authority's functions under the bill.
Clause one hundred and fifty-eight provides for on-site inspections of business premises to review records and documents, and clause one hundred and sixty-one goes further and provides that where a resolution authority has reasonable cause to believe a direction has not been complied with or an offence committed under the FIRB, an investigator can be appointed who can.
Obviously, confidentiality is important in a sensitive area such as resolution, but equally so is the ability for a resolution authority to exchange information with other resolution authorities, both domestic and overseas, to facilitate coordinated approaches to resolution. And these issues are covered by clauses one hundred and seventy-one to one hundred and seventy-three.
一百七十三條的FIRB， 一百七十一條設定出義務，管轄決議權限和有角色的人士。一百七十二條管轄金融機構實行決議權限的條款，和一百七十三條管轄向海外決議權限。
所以轉向到 funding，  one of the principal objectives of resolution is ensuring that the costs primarily fall on creditors and shareholders， rather than on the the taxpayer or the public purse， but expenses will inevitably be incurred by the resolution authority in conducting resolution， and it may be necessary for some temporary
所以需要有機制來確保任何損失在於此類開支可以收回，而第十二部分的FIRB處理此問題。所以條文一百七十五規定由決議機構在準備和執行決議時所產生的費用，以及財政部長在任命決議機構成員時所產生的費用，可以收回。
And as we can't predict in advance whether any and which type of FI will fail, clause 179 provides for the financial secretary to make case-specific regulations for the imposition of a levy in the case of a given resolution, including the class of entity to be levied and the methodology for assessing the amount or share of levy.
As we've discussed several times now, the Hong Kong resolution authorities will not be required by the bill to accept or take part in a group-wide resolution conducted by the home jurisdiction resolution authority. But the local resolution authorities may, however, elect to support or recognise overseas resolution actions where this meets the.
practice.
Thank you.
兩間商業。
同事有冇咩問題啊？
包括了非常 swift outline of the bill, 周。
188，聚焦於認可，和條文189，處理支援。
The resolution authority will be given a period of seven days to decide whether to resolve, and during that time, presentation of a petition is effectively stayed.
而 whilst the FIRB, as some of the delegates discussed this morning, sets out the framework of tools which a resolution authority can use to bring about orderly resolution.
And as FI's operating cross-border tend to be relatively highly integrated, meaning that an entity operating in one jurisdiction may be dependent on related group companies in other jurisdictions for funding, provision of services and in other ways.
And finally, clause 201 empowers the financial secretary to amend the list of protective schemes, such as the deposit protection scheme in Schedule 1. This is related to the objectives for resolution.
Clause 197 follows the key attributes and the provisions commonly found in other regulatory ordinances, in providing protection to the resolution authority and its staff and those assisting them from civil liability for actions taken in good faith in performing functions under the FIRB.
在such cases, cross-border cooperation may be key to securing orderly resolution, which preserves continuity for the benefit of all jurisdictions, and by maintaining the group as a going concern is less value-destructive than a jurisdiction-by-jurisdiction disintegration. So, recognising all of this, the key attributes required jurisdictions to provide.
Swift and transparent processes to enable effect to be given to foreign resolution measures, and this can be by way of recognition, or by using the domestic regime to support overseas measures. And Part 13 of the FIRB provides for both of these avenues, with clauses 185 to
所以，最後，Part 14 是一collection of miscellaneous but nevertheless important provisions. Obviously, the entire purpose of resolution could be frustrated if before the resolution authority gets a chance to act, a creditor petitions for the winding up of the relevant financial institution. So, clause 190 provides a mechanism by which
Resolution authorities will need to develop processes and procedures to make those tools practically operational. So, to provide guidance and clarity to the industry and to the public more generally on these operational matters, clause 194 provides that a resolution authority can issue a code of
And he can also add to, but not remove from, the list of liabilities in Schedule 5, and that's the list of liabilities which are excluded from bailing. So they cannot be bailed in by a resolution authority. And finally, Part 15 of the FIRB is just the miscellaneous consequential amendments to other ordinances, and that concludes.
and.
valuation of companies and and claims processes.
聽一聽嚇，呢兩個審裁處嗰個職能，唔該啊。好啊。
the the first tribunal is designed to look at
Could enable them to to take a view on on the proposals being put forward to improve resolvability.
你係咩角色啊？係，我係Mr. Cam。Thank you. So, so there are two, the two tribunals. So the, the, the.
Whether resolution authority has given an instruction to remove an impediment to resolution.
有looked at what they actually did get as a result of resolution, and he will have run a model of what a hypothetical liquidation would have looked like if the institution had gone into liquidation immediately before resolution.
啊！主席，我可可唔可以叫嗯局方介紹下嗰兩個審裁處嗰個組成同埋個功能，同埋喺呢個成個即係resolution regime入邊咧，喺邊一個stage呢兩個審裁處咧係會可能會有一個發揮到個功能咧？我我想。
Because that can occur during business as normal times, and indeed should occur during that time, it's thought that there should be a dedicated avenue of appeal for a financial institution to to to to query or to object to that provision. So the first, the Resolvability Review Tribunal, will be focused very much on looking at the.
Is that request necessary to make this institution more resolvable? Is there another means by which the institution could be made more resolvable other than the route that the RA is electing for? So the way we see this kind of working would be that the RA will be in discussions with the financial institution.
And will identify an impediment to resolvability, and will suggest to the institution that this would be a way to resolve it. We expect that the institution may come back with alternative proposals that may meet the may actually achieve the same effect. So we expect there to be a sort of interactive process. But at the end of the day, if the RA issues
一個方向， to remove an impediment， and the institution objects to that. It has a should have a right of appeal to the resolvability review tribunal. and The idea would be that the tribunal will be chaired by a person that's qualified to be a judge, but would have members that would be have expertise that
the the second tribunal is is a bit different because that tribunal is the the compensation tribunal so here we would have shareholders and creditors who consider that the so the the independent valuer will have have conducted evaluation and he will
The aim of the resolution compensation tribunal. So, if somebody objects to that those valuations and said that that that can't be right, the aim of the resolution compensation tribunal is to have a look at that and see whether that is reasonable or whether it's so unreasonable that no reasonable valuer could have could have come to that to that view.
And so, so, so that tribunal, if you like, would be a much more public tribunal in the sense that many creditors or shareholders would object. And again, we we see it as as chaired by someone who's qualified for for appointment as a judge, but with lay members, if if you like, that have expertise in areas such as
嗯嗯。
第二第二個問題咧，就關於嗰個誒。
That is my question.
啊啊，Right，OK，主席唔該，我我繼續想有啲問題啦，嗯。
to serve these tribunals. now because already I have seen many tribunals are very difficult to find the eligible type of people to sit on there.
Okay, are these two tribunals part of the fixture, or will they be just appointed after a resolution regime is triggered off?
confining ourselves to serving members of the judiciary, and actually we have cast, if I may say, the word net quite wide, in order to address the particular question of availability of suitable persons with such judicial judicial experience.
I think the idea would be to have them appointed ahead of time, in the sense of having a panel available, so that they could be quickly constituted. So, in the same way that we have other tribunals under other ordinances, we would periodically identify who would be a chair and who could.
會被 panel members， and then at the time members could be selected from those panels to sit on the the tribunal. Yeah, Mr. Chairman, my my concern is I think the judiciary is very very stretched in terms of manpower and time, and there are a lot of tribunals I mean in operation under.
our you know legal system, and of course there are a lot of tribunals also servicing the financial service industry, and I'm just wondering whether we have the the you know the right people and the right number of people.
Thank you. Long time. Yeah, thank you, Mr. Chairman. The in fact, in schedules eight and nine, we have set out the the composition and also the modal sovereignty of the two tribunals, the resolvability assessment and also the review, and also the resolution compensation. Now, actually.
Mr. Long has pointed out a very actually pertinent question, and and on this one we have actually consulted with the judiciary administrator, and/or who who in turn actually has taken also soundings with the chief justice. This is why in Schedule A in the actual Section Two there we have stipulated.
啊，Karen。
誒，我睇下有冇補充。誒，阿Mr. Kevin有一個point補充嚇。
我哋而家呢個草案委員會嘅委員，如果已經唔在席嘅下一屆。
呢啲噉嘅條例同埋嗰啲扶例咧，係因為有好多個嘅。
未都未入，有啲地方咧，譬如頭先等緊嗰啲嘅誒嘅誒。
啊！等等嗰啲詳細嗰啲誒關誒嗰啲資料咧，係要擠落去嘅。咁所以我哋會係誒會咁做。
that the in terms of the composition of the chairperson, we have mentioned that it will be a it can be a former justice of appeal, or former judge, former recorder, former deputy judge, or actually a third category are those who are eligible for appointment as such. So we we are not.
立法程序嘅問題啦，嗱呢呢呢條標咧，就算畀我哋喺呢一個誒setting過咗之後咧，誒，我想問一問局方，你哋根本係之後仲有好多嘅誒subsidiary legislation係要做嘅，咁即係話你過之後，就算喺呢一個誒立法年度。
過咗，即係話要喺新一嘅立法會咧，你先會去過嗰啲嘅誒附屬條例草案。咁即係話咧，但係你未過個附屬條例草案之前咧，呢條嘅誒草條例草案係冇可能去去去去and act㗎嘛？係咪？我我嘅解讀啱唔啱？唔該。
誒，劉生誒，主席誒，啱嘅。誒，我哋誒建議計劃，我哋遲啲，我哋都係再討詳細討論，睇下會員嘅意見咧，即係議員嘅意見咧。就我哋其實我哋建議嘅咧，就係話將呢個誒呢個誒草案嘅佢入邊有一個大綱，同埋都有好詳細嘅誒嘅叫做provisions啊，呢啲噉嘅條款咧。
我哋係會喺大江裏邊誒討論之後咧，係成即係個草案係成即係叫做成形之後咧。我哋其實就唔會即刻係將呢個草案咧建議立法會係即刻畀個生效嘅。我哋會其實我哋而家咧亦都係做緊一啲嘅準備功夫，因為我哋其實好多呢啲噉嘅誒room誒。
長程咧喺嗰個誒熱喺國際嗰個FSB啊，佢哋噉樣嘅誒層面度咧，都仲係好多係有啲針著啊嗰啲傾緊。所以咧，我哋誒心目中諗嘅咧，就可能我哋喺嗰個建誒呢個草案當佢係誒即係立咗法之後enactment之後咧，其實我哋估計可能需要。
要差唔多大概一年到嘅時間咧，係將嗰個誒嗰啲附例咧，要同嗰啲業界諮詢啊，睇下國際嗰個誒金融穩定個理事會嗰方面啊個進展嘅方面咧，係陸續咁去做落去。咁所以我哋估計嘅生效嗰個時間咧，應該就係呢啲條例之後嘅。咁起碼因為佢哋呢啲條例。
有好多咧，誒，當然有啲比較上係可以話係誒詳細一啲、濕水一啲嘅，我哋唔需要等佢全部都喺曬度。但係我哋會建議畀委員會考慮嘅咧，就係話呢啲主要誒，到時我哋會解釋就係話主要嗰啲嘅附例咧係需要做咗先嘅。如果唔係嘅話，係做誒做即係行唔到嘅噉。
但係誒，佢嘅點解我哋都係話呢個草案咁重要性？點解唔等緊年後咧？因為咧誒嗰個誒，其實呢個情況咧好多誒國家咧都係噉樣樣去誒去係去誒做緊佢哋嘅條例，譬如有啲國家嘅條例，佢哋都未給誒未，譬如誒英國咁咯，佢哋保險業佢哋。
Just to mention that we we are starting to work already on the subsidiary legislation, having got the bill into Legco. So we're trying to work simultaneously on that. As Mr Lau said, some of it we can work on now. Some of it is still moving slightly at the international level, but it's important.
that we get the bill enacted because that that's that's a very visible sign to the FSB that that we are committed to this process and then we can explain to them that we are working to sort out the the subsidiary legislation. Not all of the subsidiary legislation is is vital to the full operation of the the bill. A lot of it goes
more to making all the the items more operational. So we are in the process of kind of prioritising and scheduling how we can draft the the subsidiary legislation and how we can go through the various rounds of consultation that we will need in order to make sure that it that it works and that it's acceptable. 啊，主席啊，我我真係感覺上嗱嗰個附屬條例草案我。
我我感覺上咧唔會畀呢個主體法例會斷咯，一定。咁如果你下一屆換屆嘅時候咧，各位委員可能即係新嘅啦，可能都係啊，主席啊，我唔知啊。噉我我諗咧，我希望局方咧，就算你話你個你你你個你個時間表就好即係好樂觀啊。咁下一屆全部。
新嘅委，如果呢一個委員會啊，即係即係財經事務委員會屬下嘅條例草案委員會等等，都係一啲全新嘅誒立法會議員嘅時候咧，我我就覺得你哋都要咧差唔多由頭啊，將將成條條例草案同一啲新嘅，即係如果你審議附屬法例嘅時候，如果我
誒。
阿梁儀。主席。
應噉樣樣嚇，畀翻我睇。我希望我哋。
我希望我哋做close by close嘅時候咧，我哋去到嗰啲地方嘅時候，可以揸住個表咧，逐個對照，究竟我哋傾到嘅時候佢有咩意見噉樣。係啊，好啊。
因為經常換屆嘅立法會嚇，噉啊以前嗰啲法例通過咗嗰啲咧，有好多新嘅議員都未必知道嘅，咁所以我哋係誒必須要尊重，即係而家嗰個立法會嘅職能咧，我哋係要誒。
即係主席，我我諗佢哋真係要畀好多心機去幫佢哋去做翻一個即係即係功夫去令介紹翻呢條條例草案。因為如果新一屆立法會嘅同事完全冇一個咁呢一個審議呢條條例草案經驗時，要睇附屬法例咧，我覺得係一個即係好大好大嘅問題嚟嘅，主席。係啊，好啊。但係我我。
我相信政府都誒知道你呢個關注啦。咁當然我亦都希望你下一屆會翻翻嚟啦，係咪？咁誒誒，所有嘅法例咧都唔會話一通過就即刻係實施嘅。有好多時候都會有一啲比較複雜嘅咧，都需要兩三年嘅時間去做一啲附屬法例嚟到做準。
準備嘅呢個都唔係單單咧，即係而家我哋見到呢一條誒條例草案係噉樣嚇，咁所以亦都唔應該咧，係因為誒有一啲比較即係誒複雜嘅條例草案咧，係需要長嘅時間，噉我哋就唔唔喺現階段咧就去做呢啲嘢。咁誒當然咧就。
就係話，如果係有緩解嘅情況底下咧，可能誒往後再進一步去審議一啲附屬法例嘅時候咧，就新嘅議員可能會問多啲嘢啦嚇。咁誒，我相信政府到時候亦都會咧係做一啲比較詳細嘅解説嚇。咁但係依個亦都不代表咧，就係話誒。
有條例草案嚟嘅時候，我哋都係要去盡力去審議嘅。啊，唔係，主席，我真係想提醒翻政府，你要同我哋做多啲介紹嘅工作，同埋即係嚇做多啲功夫咯，應該係。上一次我都誒提過政府啦嚇，誒喺我哋誒審議嘅期間咧，多啲同議員去接觸嚇，多介紹。
照嗰個條例草案嘅內容啊，使到大家明白啊。錢仲佳議員啊，朱迪啊，我下屆一定翻嚟㗎啦。噉啊，你哋慢慢做噉啊，你會有其他人嚟。我知嗱誒，我就但係我哋都要審議條法例啦。咁頭先我亦都多謝有誒咁多團體嚟聽意見啊，我都有聽。咁但係。
亦都有啲團體係寫咗意見落嚟，冇冇嚟講嘢嘅。噉我諗希望一如以往啦，誒，即係政府將嗰啲意見咧，即係唔係淨係支持嗰啲意見咧？對個條例有啲細節咧，有啲有啲意見嗰啲咧，你哋寫翻一個即係以前我哋做法例好興㗎啦，做翻個表，跟住咧佢哋有咩意見，你佢你哋有咩回。
主席，我想補充翻啊，阿盛仲嘉議員個個個嗰個意見啦，即係其實咁多團體都有一啲誒書面嘅意見嗱，個意見方面有啲係包含喺嗰個即係政策層面上嘅，有啲係喺個條例草案細節嗰度嘅。噉我我想其實即係兩方面啦，喺嗰個政策層。
面上有啲大嘅即係爭議性嘅嘢嘅時候咧，即係嗰個表我哋可以喺討論個政策先，即係搞掂曬曬佢先最好，即係討論咗佢先，你準備咗畀我哋睇先，跟住到再喺嗰個誒細節逐條審議嗰階段咧，亦都有個表咧，係我哋再可以睇翻。
究竟政府點樣回應每位團體，即係每個團體關於嗰個細節草誒條例草案入邊啊嗰啲嘅嘅嘅提議？即係即係我諗又分兩大類嘅事情啦。即係第一類，我係想做嗰先嘅政府喺喺喺呢個草案委員會嗰度嚇，唔該。阿梁議員嘅意見係誒相當好嘅，誒我哋都會係噉。
做嘅嚇，好嘛？請大家放心。就誒團體誒同埋嗰啲代表所發表嘅意見咧，我哋都會整理咗之後咧，就係請誒政府咧作逐一嘅喺文字上嘅嗰個回應。咁大家日後係跟進嘅時候咧，都有所依從，亦都唔會誒即係為。
好。
啊！
誒，因為。
誒，金管局介紹嘅嗰個誒。
條例草案嘅概述，大家冇咩意見啊嘛？係嘛？冇問題啊嘛？
之前咧係提過一啲嘅問題嘅，噉就誒政府亦都作咗一個。
如果冇問題嘅話咧，噉我哋就處理誒文件嘅四四三零二號文件。
誒兩個張，誒唔該主席，我我其實就係想問翻，即係關於個零二號文件嘅一啲嘅嘅嘅問題嘅，主席誒。
嘅噉，我哋而家係誒做緊呢樣嘢。噉我哋嘅估計係應該喺月底前咧，我一定交到會係畀誒議員嘅手上高，咁可以幫助議員可以睇到我哋嗰個嘅解釋嘅嚇。
嗰個回應咧都相當詳盡，我想我想睇下誒政府有冇咩補充，咁然後就誒同事有冇咩問題，好嘛？
剛才咧就誒，亦都有議員咧係誒，稍微作出一啲嘅提問啦。咁如果係冇問題嘅話咧，咁誒，我哋法律顧問咧亦都係誒。
流啊！噉我哋喺誒誒將來做逐條審議嘅時候咧，大家亦都可以將嗰啲意見咧係提翻出嚟啊！誒，我哋仲有兩份文件咧係需要處理嘅誒，剛才。
啊！政府未有一個回應嘅噉就誒，我哋嘅文件係四四三零三個文件嚇，噉就睇下政府會唔會有啲乜嘢嘅初步回應嚇。好唔好？誒，主席，我哋其實喺文件裏邊都係誒，關於嗰個誒退購機制啊，同埋講關於係誒誒，關於嗰個人員嗰方面嗰個誒。
誒，即係關於佢哋嗰個嘅處理啊，同埋關於嗰個誒跨境嗰方面，我哋都係解釋咗嗰個情況。咁亦都係誒上一誒上一次議員嘅關注，關於點樣樣去保即係保護香港或者係誒誒照顧到香港嘅利益嗰啲。咁所以我哋就係好詳細咁去解釋咗。噉我哋就誒。
誒冇再補充資料，但係我哋樂意係睇下誒議員有啲咩嘅補充嘅誒詢問，我哋係樂意係誒解答嘅。嗯，但係我都希望咧，即係因為法律顧問做咗誒比較詳細嘅一啲問題啦嚇，噉你都誒最好能夠喺記錄上咧。
係作逐條嘅嗰個回應，好唔好啊？雖然間你之前都曾經係提及過嘅，咁但係為咗誒對應翻我哋嗰啲問題啊，同埋使到大家都能夠啊，主席，我哋一定會㗎。法律顧問嗰度佢都有好多詳細嘅題目，我哋係而家我哋就係草擬誒，即係誒做緊一啲係誒誒每一條咁去去答。
好嘛？
董事長有冇其他問題？
就係二月啦。
但係，調度非常之多，向解決問題嘅概念。
O.K.噉啊，今日嘅會議咧到呢度，我哋下次會議咧。
Ordinance本身係唔會有加多一重嘅誒懲處機制畀呢啲嘅officers。
嗱，如果冇其他問題嘅話咧，就誒，我我諗今日嘅時間都差唔多啦，啊，噉我哋就順便到呢度先，噉我哋下一次咧就會誒。
睇睇誒嗰個我哋法律顧問嗰啲意見，你哋覆翻嚟，噉我哋稍微再跟進一下，噉我哋就可以進入咧就係誒逐條嘅審議嚇。
政府喺答案嘅第二部分咧，嗰個就係答翻就係the the sanctions under the existing regulatory regimes，啊，for officers, former officers等等啦。
我哋嘅下次會議係二月十五號星期一上晝八點半，嚇，誒，亦都會有另外一個會議係誒二月廿九號上晝十點九嘅，嚇，冇其他問題嘅話，我宣佈散會。
所以這些 offence 是係 quite separate offences， you know， when looking at this bill and comparing with the other， you know， already， you know， operating， you know， ordinances。 okay， okay， I see。唔該主席，好啊。
嗱，呢個係一間very general statement。我我唔，of course， there may be very specific offences under the resolution regime。但但係， in general， is my observation correct？ That the resolution regime will not
you know lay an extra layer of punishment to these officers apart from the existing offences already contained in the respective you know laws, for example the banking ordinance or the securities futures ordinance.
我我想知道咧，其實嗰個懲處機制係咪會即係，就算喺呢個條例草案生效咗之後咧，都係跟翻嗰個respective，比如話誒誒security futures ordinance啊，或者banking ordinance，即係話咧誒嗰個financial institution resolution。
Hi, yeah, with that, Mr. Chairman. Thank you. I think your your observation is correct. It's not intended to add an additional layer of of punishment. But as you note, there are specific offences within the FIRB, so so so it creates its own offences. But it doesn't it doesn't sort of add to the offences in the Bo, the SFO, or the
Insurance ordinance. So, for instance, there are information gathering powers in the FIRB. So, if the resolution authority seeks information to enable the resolution authority to work on plans and strategies for resolution, and the information is not forthcoming, then it would create certain offences for that purpose. So, it creates its own.